Can you hear us? Okay,
>> I can hear you. Great. Yeah. Can you
hear me?
>> Yep, we got you.
>> All right. Um, wanted to get with uh you
guys uh today just we're in this long
off season that's not normal for us. And
uh we've got uh the combine coming up
and all these good things happening uh
uh as we go forward here. So, it gives
us a chance to
uh talk and communicate with you on some
of the new hirings um that we've had and
then getting ourselves uh digging in on
this on this off seasonason. So, uh in
the in the coaching ranks, DeMarco
Murray, as you know, was hired as a the
running back coach and Chad O'Shea at
the wide receiver position,
excuse me. and then Andre Curtis uh will
work with David in the secondary with
the safeties and um and so uh good
additions there. We've had a couple new
quality control coaches come in likewise
and uh they'll work into the into the
mix and and help out. So it's sometimes
change can be good as as we've as we
know and and um and this gives uh I
think it's good for both sides. people
have moved on and have had opportunities
to hook on other places and uh they'll
be very successful doing that. And then
likewise the people we brought in we
feel will do the same for for us. So all
in all positive there on the personnel
side. Brett's already got his guys
digging in on things. They're sorting
everything out as you know. There's a
million different options and things
that you have to look at uh doing it.
It's um it's positive from the
standpoint of where we're picking in the
draft. Uh you give Brett those
opportunities with his with his staff
and they come up with uh with good stuff
and we look forward to adding those new
additions u to the team and then
whatever happens in free agency again
sorting all that out. Right now, the
coaches are looking at tape on that and
the the uh person approve personnel
department has uh sorted some things out
for him to look at uh and and we we roll
from there. But um a lot of lot of
moving parts going on, but all good all
good stuff uh to give us an opportunity
to be better. as coaches, we've been in
our scheme evaluations and knocking that
out in the early part of the day and the
and then in the afternoon we we do um uh
the personnel side of it. So, um nothing
set in gold for you uh or in granite
there. It's um uh it's all uh moving
along though as we as we go. So, with
that, time's yours. Ask have ask some
questions.
>> We'll kick things off with Sam McDow. Go
ahead, Sam.
>> Hey, Andy. Um,
>> hi Sam.
>> Hey. Uh,
a couple things for you. I wonder if you
could go through a couple of the the
coaches that uh more specifically like
what what did you see in Chad O'Shea and
DeMarco Murray?
>> Yeah. So, uh, Chad's got a ton of, uh,
experience. Um, he actually had been a
chief at one point in a in a backup type
coaching position, but he a quality
control position with special teams. for
coach Vermile's staff, but he's been
around. He's uh worked at a championship
caliber level with New England. Um and
he's had a lot of good good receivers
and uh done well with them. So that that
was Chad's part of it. I really like
what he brings it to. He's been in a
coordinator position where he's got a
good feel for the whole the whole um the
way things are put together from a whole
standpoint. And then DeMarco Murray is
uh we know DeMarco as a as a football
player and the great football player
that he was. Demarco has been at the
University of Oklahoma, done a nice job
there for six years. um and had some
good running backs and I just thought
him coming in in that position would
there would be a strength to that and
not only from an experience standpoint
but also um the way he goes about
teaching things and uh I think he adds a
nice nice addition there.
Excuse me. And then um Andre Curtis um
I've tried to hire Andre before um uh
when Steve came in uh Spagnola came in.
They've been together at three different
places and uh he's actually worked with
every member of our defensive staff and
uh it was kind of that was an easy one
to plug in and go. And it's a it's great
for Rod to have an opportunity to move
on and uh do his own thing there uh um
at at Arizona. So that's um that's a
plus for him.
>> And then as you formulate your offseason
blueprint, have you received any
indication from from Travis at all about
his plans for next year?
>> Uh no, there is communication though.
That's the that's the main thing, Sam.
And so I I always go, I've said this
before to you, just um as long as
there's communication, I'm good. That
means people want to move forward. And
uh and I think that's where Travis is.
I'm not trying to put words in his mouth
at all. And I try to give give him some
space here. He's been doing this a long
time. And he can sort all that out as he
goes forward. But uh we're proceeding uh
with that and and there is communication
going on. We'll go next to Pete Sweeney.
Pete,
>> coach,
>> I was just curious maybe how having a
top 10 pick, obviously not a place that
you want to be, has maybe intensified
things for the personnel staff and and
just some ways that maybe you've seen
that.
>> Yeah, Pete, you try to find some
positives and and sitting where you're
where you're at and why you're there and
and and then the positives are you get
yourself geared down and and get better.
And uh so if this has a chance to help
you help you get better and that's how
Brett feels and that's the way he's
going about it and nobody wants to be
picking at ninth but uh we are that's
the reality of it and so you dig in and
you you put a plan together and and go
for it uh the best you can. And he's had
his guys in here. They they done a
couple lockdowns already where he's had
him in for a couple weeks and um they
live in that room and go through all
these different players and uh and so
you know good things normally come out
of those meetings and look forward to
how the draft goes.
>> We'll go to Todd Lebo next. Todd.
>> Hey coach. Uh couple quick things here.
Um you know I know there's this civil
case going on with Rashid. I want to ask
you specifically about that, but does
that thing hanging out there change
anything you guys are considering at the
wide receiver position either in free
agency or uh the draft?
>> I would tell you no. I mean, I can't
comment on Rashid's situation. I mean,
it's Listen, it's in law enforcement's
hands, so I I there's no comment there,
but I would tell you no, not right now.
That's not it.
And then uh as far as like the cap, I
know you guys will do all the work and
Brett's doing that stuff to get you down
to where you can do some free agency
things, but is this going to be one of
those years where you just maybe can't
spend tons of money in free agency
because of where you are?
>> Yeah, that's that's Listen, it's all
pieces to a puzzle here. So, you go
through and you you evaluate that and
see where you can spend, what's out
there. free agency is a different it's a
little bit different animal and how you
how you handle it and um so uh we'll
we'll see how things go. I mean we're
kind of sorting through all of that as
we go. As you know, the combine ends up
being an area where people talk and um
you know, you've got agents, coaches,
GMs, everybody together. And so, you
know, they people have a tendency to uh
you hear things, right? And people talk
and you keep your ears open and your
mouth shut and listen and see see what's
going on. But, um until the first of,
you know, until the new league year
starts, nobody can really dig in on it
and and go. But people like to talk in
this league. That's why you're making a
living at it, right? That's that's how
it goes.
>> We'll go next to Jesse Newle. Jesse,
>> hey Andy. Um, you guys have had reunions
before with like Kareem and Guju.
Obviously, you guys know Tyreek really
well and he's a free agent now. I just
wondered in general, how do you evaluate
whether a reunion makes sense for you
guys to bring back a player like that?
Yeah, listen, we go we go through
everything and everybody. I mean, that's
how Brad does. And I I don't even know
if Tyreek is healthy right now. I mean,
to to do anything. So, that's uh um I'm
sure he's working hard on that part of
it and trying to get get that all
straight. But, um yeah, I mean, we
listen, we talk about everything. So
it's not there's nothing in you know
nothing happening there but I it's we we
know what you know and that he's out
there and and cranking away trying to
get himself back to where he can he can
play you know period and you know
>> we'll go next to Herby Tilpy. Herby
>> hey coach good afternoon. How are you?
>> Goodbye.
>> Hey two questions here for you. The
first one that you can't help but notice
you're not on the media schedule for
next week. Is there any reason why
you're not going to the combine?
>> I couldn't take you guys anymore than
this right here. Herby,
>> I'll tell you, Herby, um I listen, I had
a little knee knee procedure done, so
I'm uh I'm I'm on IR for about a second
here. Not long. free agency. What does a
player need to have characteristic-wise,
work ethic wise, not necessarily
physically for them to fit into what you
guys have built here?
>> Yeah, you you got to come in with the
right attitude for sure. And um
you know, again, that's uh that's a big
part of this thing. And and there there
is a fit there. literally there's
there's a there's a certain uh
expectation
um that we've got and we didn't we
didn't reach that uh this past year. So,
you know, it's important that that we
take care of business on a coaching from
a coaching standpoint,
uh, from a, you know, organizational
standpoint, whether it's personnel or or
front office, uh, you know, and and make
sure we keep, uh, keep the expectations
high and aggressive. Um, and then make
sure we bring in the right people to be
able to do that and handle that. And so
that's um that's the whole, you know,
that's the fit you're talking about.
That's what we're what we're working
through.
>> And then you talked about how the
coaching staff's going through scheme
and everything during the day. For the
offensive coaching staff specifically,
what is it you're wanting them to kind
of lock in on from tape to improve upon?
I know you can't give specifics, but
what are you kind of wanting them
general theme wise to kind of improve
upon and maybe check out the rest of the
league for some wrinkles and everything?
Yeah. So, we look at everything and
everybody. I mean, that's that's how
this league is. Uh try not to miss
anything there. Uh right now, execution
becomes the important thing to me. Uh
and how you go about that, the
discipline of it and how you go about
it. Uh and the trust within one another,
all the things that make up uh a good
offense. Um, you narrow things down to
what you think your guys do the best and
then you coach it uh with discipline and
uh with expectation that this is what
this is where we're going right here.
And it's your responsibility as a player
to make sure that you're focused in on
that. At the same time, the coach has
got to give the player direction to get
there. So,
We have time for two more here. We'll go
first to Matt Derek. Matt,
>> coach, a couple of questions, but one
related to what Nick was just asking you
there. Um,
you know, it's when you're do you
anticipate that with especially with the
new staff and everything that you're
going to have a lot of changes to the
offense, a lot of changes to what you're
doing and that maybe we've seen in
versus the past couple of years.
>> Well, there's always change. I mean,
every year there's there's there's
change that takes place. Is it a
wholesale change? No. Um, but we'll
we'll figure out the guys we have and
what they do the best and we'll put them
in a position there uh to exploit their
strengths and then to work on their
weaknesses to get them better. And uh um
and so that's the base premise there.
And then execution becomes an important
thing and how you go about doing that at
a high level. And so that's coaching and
playing mixed together to make that
happen. And uh you know, you want to
make sure though that you get these guys
in the right position to where they at
least have an opportunity to do that.
And and then they've got a
responsibility to make sure they up
their game to do the right things at the
right time.
And you mentioned some of the things
that you like about DeMarco Murray as a
coach. There were reports that you had
looked at some other guys and maybe
bringing back Dylan McAuliff and and
maybe Duce Staley. Um what what was the
ultimate factor for you in choosing
DeMarco and and what did you have to do
to convince him to leave Oklahoma?
Because it sounds like he turned down
some other opportunities to stay there.
>> Yeah, he did do that. Um and was doing
well there. I mean, he could have stayed
there. He's a legend there. So, he could
have stayed there for forever probably,
you know. Uh but he wanted to get in the
National Football League. He wanted to
be here. Um and
uh learn I think hiring Eric Benemy I
think is a big thing because uh um
Eric's if Eric's coaching the running
backs, he's the best running back coach
in the National Football League. So he
had he had an opportunity to go back and
do that again last year and and so he we
hire him here as the offensive
coordinator. Well, if I'm a running back
coach, what a great opportunity to
learn. There's nobody better to learn
from than Eric for that particular spot.
And I think that intrigued him. Eric
recruited him out of high school. So, um
they they had they've known each other
for a number of years. And um that's
that was another piece of it. But I
think I always look to see who works
well together and what I think
anticipate will work well together. I
wanted to bring a young guy in that was
a a guy that was ambitious to learn and
and um and I thought DeMarco did a heck
of a job. We we talked to a lot of
running back coaches and I just thought
that this was a pretty good fit.
We'll go to our last one here with Vah.
Vah, go ahead.
>> Hey, Andy. Uh, I'll have a followup
also, Kelsey. Andy, hope you get off the
IR uh here fast. Um,
>> what you know, you've mentioned a few
times about a lot of moving parts and
all the change and it it I just wonder
if you would how you would describe what
to what degree you're kind of
invigorated by this.
>> Well, no. I mean, listen, I love
challenges. Every year is a challenge.
This one presents a little different
because of what we're coming off of
after this last year. Nobody wants that.
Fans don't want that. Organization
doesn't want that. You you coaches,
players, they don't want that. So, you
dig in and you you you work to fix those
fix the problems that you think were in
place and and take care of business
there. So, that's that's what we're
doing. And, uh there's always change in
this league. So that always presents um
you know different different challenges
there and uh but that's part of the the
NFL. uh whether it's coaches, whether
it's players, I mean, they're things
that are they're moving parts. And so
when you're building it back up here,
then you're looking at what fits and
putting the pieces of the puzzle back
together, whether it's coaches, whether
it's again players, a lot of variables
with free agency, with the draft, uh
postdraft, the things that go on there,
um potentially picking up people. So,
it's uh you know, it's going to continue
for a while and and then eventually you
get this group together and you have an
opportunity to train them through the
off season and then up through training
camp and it's great to see how that
grows.
>> And then just to follow up, I I wonder
what you can tell us about Patrick's
progress and and how you see him kind of
reintegrating in in the weeks and months
to come.
>> Yeah, he's around here all the time. Uh
spends a ton of time here. seven hours a
day. And um he's in there cranking away,
making progress every day. And uh it's
great to see he and Julie, the real
trainer, she she uh they they she grinds
on him and makes sure that he stays on
task and challenges him and everything
else and and he keeps showing up. So
that's uh that's about half the battle
on these things when you have these
injuries that you show up and it's not
going to be a pleasant thing every day.
Uh you got to fight through it and you
got to attack the you know the challenge
of the workout and uh rehab. So he's
doing a great job with that.
>> Thank you so much, coach. We appreciate
the time.
>> All right, Kelsey.
>> Thanks.